Welcome to our training on how to read Amazon Business Reports.
Amazon Business Reports can help you monitor your product's sales, traffic, and conversion rates.
They can also show the effects of changes that you have made in your selling strategy.
Business reports are found in Seller Central under the Reports tab.
These reports are available if you have the professional selling plan.
Let's look at a few examples of  how the data in the business reports can help you understand your
sales.
In order to make a sale, customers must visit your product's detail page.
Sessions and page view metrics show the traffic to your product's detail page.
The more traffic, the greater the chance of a sale.
Page view metrics display the total number of visits to your product's detail page.
A customer may visit the same detail page multiple times a day or week.
Each of these visits counts as a single page view.
The sessions metric displays the number of customers that are visiting your page per day.
A customer may visit the same detail page multiple times in one day, but as this is the same customer,
all of the customer's visits for that day will only count as one session.
Maria can't decide which wine glasses to buy.
She keeps visiting any company's Stemless Glasses detail page.
Maria visits any company's Stemless Glasses product detail page seven times on Saturday.
On Tuesday, she visits the page again to buy the glasses.
The page view value in the reports is eight, as she visits the detail page for the glasses eight
times in total.
The sessions value is two, as Maria is the same customer visiting and has visited on two separate
days.
Comparing report metrics can help you determine the reasons why sales have increased, decreased,
or leveled off.
Comparisons can also help you decide if using other Amazon selling tools may help your sales.
Here are a few examples of things you may want to consider when there are changes in business report
data.
If your page views are high but your sales are low, ask, is your product priced correctly?
Could your product be better described?
Could your product images be better?
Should you consider becoming a prime seller or using fulfillment by Amazon?
More questions to ask yourself.
How do the session and page views correlate to your percentage featured offer?
Do you get more traffic when you are the featured offer?
Featured offer considerations.
If you have low featured offer percentage and low sales but your product detail page has had high
page views,
you may want to consider reducing the price of your product to try and become the featured offer.
Also, consider using the automatic pricing tool so that you can match or beat the featured offer
price.
Fulfillment by Amazon considerations.
If you have a high number of page views and sessions for your product,
you may want to consider that product for fulfillment by Amazon, FBA.
Using FBA can help convert page views to sales.
You can also compare the data in the reports before, during and after an event to determine its
success.
Events include Prime Day, being the featured offer, advertising and campaigns, coupons and deals,
automatic pricing for the product, an increase or decrease in the price of the product.
Sales trends are useful in seeing how your product is selling over time.
Here are a few examples of questions to ask yourself about the product and why sales increased or
decreased.
Is your product seasonal?
Are you no longer the featured offer?
Have you changed the price of the product?
Was the product a temporarily in demand product owing to social media coverage?
Was your product out of stock?
The seller performance report shows your performance metrics for customer satisfaction.
It is important to regularly review this report,
especially the return and feedback data.
Reviewing and acting on this data will help ensure that your account remains in good health.
Amazon Business Reports provide a wealth of information that can be downloaded into a CSV file or
viewed in Seller Central.
This concludes the training on how to read Amazon Business Reports.
Thank you, and happy selling in the Amazon Store.